Ammar El refay Kandel

FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

merom8703@gmail.com| Github | LinkedIn | Portfolio

SUMMARY

Full-Stack Software Developer with a passion for coding and creating responsive web applications. I have experience working with remote developers, and advanced proficiencies in HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, Ruby, Ruby on Rails, and React/Redux. I also prefer working at a startup because it gives me an opportunity to understand the ins-and-outs of the industry, and to take on tasks I might not have at a larger company.

SKILLS

Front-End: JavaScript, React, Redux, jQuery, HTML5, CSS3

Back-End: Ruby, Rails, MySQL

Tools & Methods: Git, GitHub, Heroku, Netlify, Mobile/Responsive Development, RSpec, TDD, Chrome Dev Tools

Professional: Remote Pair-Programming, Teamwork, Mentoring

EXPERIENCE

HIGHLIGHTED PERSONAL PROJECTS Freelance - Full Stack Web Developer Remote

Dec, 2020 - Present

Order-From-Restaurants — This static website template. Help users to allow their clients to search for near restaurants.

Built with: (Html - Css)

Tic-Tac-Toe-Game — This is a game that makes users/players have a fun time.

Built with: (Ruby - RSpec)

Ruby-Linter — This project helps developers check some of the unexpected actions in the code.

• Built with: (Ruby - RSpec)

MICROVERSE

Remote

Mentor (Volunteer)

Dec, 2020 - Present

- Mentored junior web developers, providing technical support through code reviews.
- Proposed improvements to code organization to improve code quality and overall performance.
- Provided advice and tips on how to maintain motivation to maintain longevity in the program.

EDUCATION

MICROVERSE
Remote Full Stack Web Development Program, Full Time

Dec, 2020 - Present

- Spent 1300+ hours mastering algorithms, data structures, and full-stack development while simultaneously developing projects with Ruby, Rails, JavaScript, React, and Redux.
- Developed skills in remote pair-programming using GitHub, industry-standard gitflow, and daily standups to communicate and collaborate with international remote developers.